pizzahut.ca 2013-12-25

# Pizza Hut's Personal Info & Privacy Policy | Pizza Hut Canada

## PRIVACY POLICY

### YUM! RESTAURANTS INTERNATIONAL (CANADA) COMPANY

Yum! Restaurants International (Canada) Company and its affiliates (collectively, "we" or "Yum!") work with our Pizza Hut, Taco Bell and KFC franchisees across Canada to run great restaurants.

Yum provides automated and centralized order processing and delivery dispatch solutions so that we, along with our franchisees, can deliver exceptional service to our customers. For this purpose we collect and use some basic personal information about customers.

We also collect and use personal information about our employees and franchisees

This privacy policy explains those personal information practices.

#### What Personal Information do we Collect?

_Information collected from Customers_

Typically, when a customer contacts us, either by telephone or through our website, we collect customers' names, addresses, phone numbers, credit card numbers (if that is how they choose to pay), email address (if the customer orders through our web-site), order history and any comments that a customer may provide to us. Yum! provides the information you provide to Yum! to the independent franchisee that serves you. The information we provide to such franchisee is governed by their personal information practices and privacy practices. You should consult with the franchisee who serves you to find out how and why they collect and use personal information. 

_Information Collected from Potential Franchisee_

Typically, when a potential franchisee contacts us we collect the potential franchisee's names, addresses, phone numbers, email address as well as financial information and work/education background and history.

_Information Collected from Employees/Potential Employees_

With respect to potential employees we collect only that information that is reasonably necessary to assess an individual's application for and suitability for employment and to administer our employees. The information that is collected includes names, addresses, phone numbers, email address, bank accounts as well as information regarding performance, work/education background and history and such information contained in a résumé or that is obtained from references.

Personal information does not include the business contact information of our franchisees/employees such as the Yum! business telephone, mobile phone and email addresses of our employees, nor does it include the name and business title of Yum! employees.

### Why do we collect Personal Information?

_Customer Personal Information_

We collect, use and maintain personal information (including delivery address, email, and past order history) for the following service purposes:

  * to fulfill orders;
  * to anticipate order preferences when you contact us again; and
  * to provide faster, better service.

If you tell us that you do not wish us to keep the above information, we will destroy it. However, at present our systems cannot track these types of requests beyond its destruction. As such, if you order from us again, we will collect this information upon submission of the new order and it will not be automatically destroyed. Refer to the section below entitled _How can I access and update my Personal Information?_ for instructions on how to notify us of your preferences. In that case, you will need to provide personal information each time that you contact us to place an order.

We may also use personal information we keep for marketing purposes such as to contact you (whether by email, telephone, direct mail, or another medium of communication) about:

  * promotions or contests;
  * new products or product promotions;
  * special offers;
  * asking for feedback on new products;
  * asking for feedback on your dining experience and our customer service; and
  * responding to your comments or concerns. 

Personal information is shared with our affiliates, franchisees, agents, representatives, contractors and service providers, some of whom may be located outside of Canada, for the purposes described above. Our affiliates are subject to and abide by this privacy policy. We require our affiliates, franchisees, agents, representatives, contractors and service providers to use personal information we share with them only in accordance with this privacy policy and the applicable law.

We will not use or disclose your personal information for marketing purposes, however, we may disclose personal information in connection with a reorganization or an acquisition. If you tell us that you do not wish us to do so, refer to the section below entitled _How can I access and update my Personal Information?_ for instructions on how to notify us of your preferences.

We do not disclose customer's personal information to others without your consent, except as required or permitted by law.

_Franchisee Applicants Personal Information_

We use personal information of franchisee applicants only for the purpose of determining whether or not to grant a franchise to the applicant. If the applicant is successful we will also retain and use the information collected in the course of assessing the application for a franchise for use in connection with the franchise agreement. We may retain applicant information for a period of twelve months from the date of application for the purpose of assessing an individual's suitability for other franchise opportunities with our organization. Applicant's personal information is destroyed after twelve months from the date of application if no franchise rights are granted. Disposal is executed by shredding or another secure disposal mechanism.

_Applicants for Employment Personal Information_

We use personal information of applicants for employment only for the purpose of assessing suitability for employment. If the applicant is successful we will also retain and use the information collected in the course of assessing the application for employment. We may retain applicant information for a period of twelve months from the date of application for the purpose of assessing an individual's suitability for other employment opportunities with our organization. Applicant personal information is destroyed after twelve months from the date of application if no employment with our organization materializes in that time period. Disposal is executed by shredding or another secure disposal mechanism. 

_Employee Personal Information_

We collect and use personal information about our employees for employment purposes, such as:

  * to manage an individual's employment relationship with us;
  * to evaluate an individual's performance in their job;
  * to administer compensation and insurance, employment and retirement related benefits;
  * to promote the health and safety of the workplace;
  * to accommodate an employee in a return to work program after a disability; and
  * if applicable, to investigate whether to terminate an employment relationship or to make a decision about whether to terminate employment.

From time to time we may monitor emails and computer use of our systems by employees. This is done in order to ensure that company systems and email infrastructure are used exclusively for legitimate business purposes and to protect our systems from unauthorized use. We try to minimize intrusiveness when we do this.

We also may use personal information in our files about individuals who were, but are no longer, employed by us, for some of the purposes listed above to the extent necessary to satisfy an obligation which survives employment or to assess a former employee's suitability for new employment with us and to contact individuals about such potential employment opportunities. 

Employees are made aware of the purpose for which their personal information is collected, used or disclosed through the availability of this _Privacy Statement_.

_Sharing of Employee Personal Information_

We may retain a service provider to perform on our behalf certain administrative services in support of our business. Such service providers include our payroll service and our outsourced benefit and RRSP carrier. Accordingly, in certain instances service providers may be provided with personal information to the extent that it is necessary in the performance of those specific administrative services provided to us. We require service providers to use and take steps to protect any personal information we provide to them. At a minimum, they must take precautions to hold information secure and they must adhere to the principles set out in this _Privacy Statement_. Personal information may also be shared with our affiliates. Our affiliates are subject to and abide by this privacy policy.

Sometimes, individuals or organizations may ask for information about our existing or former employees. Typically we do not disclose personal information about our employees or former employees unless specifically directed to do so by the employee or if we are compelled by law or a court order. However, in a tender or other competitive bid process we may be asked to provide information about our individual employees and their credentials, including their résumé and we will disclose this information in these circumstances.

Sometimes our former employees ask us to share their personal information with other organizations for the purposes of an employment reference. We do not provide employment references other than to confirm the position or positions held and the employee's tenure with us. An employee's request for a reference means that we are authorized to disclose such information to the person seeking the reference, or a person acting on their behalf. 

### How do we safeguard Personal Information?

We retain the personal information that we collect for so long as such personal information is useful or may be required. Except where required or authorized at law, when personal information is no longer required for the purposes for which it has been collected, such personal information (if it continues to be in our possession) will be made anonymous or destroyed. 

Personal Information may be stored and processed outside of Canada, including the United States. As such, personal information may be accessed by foreign governmental authorities and otherwise in accordance with the laws applicable in the jurisdiction in which it is stored.

### How can I access and update my Personal Information?

We make efforts to ensure that the personal information we use and keep is accurate, complete and up-to-date. You may request to review and/or correct your personal information.

Also you may contact us to tell us, if you do not wish us to:

  * Keep your personal information for future service purposes;
  * Use your personal information for marketing purposes; or
  * Share you personal information for marketing purposes.

Please feel free to contact us if have any questions about the collection, use, disclosure or storage of personal information by service providers located outside of Canada, or wish to access written information about the policies and practices utilized in connection with service providers outside of Canada.

Contact us at <http://www.pizzahut.ca/contact-us/> or by calling us at 1-866-364-0825.

### How do you monitor compliance with these practices?

Our Director, Human Resources is the person responsible for our personal information practices and monitors ongoing compliance with our privacy policy. You can contact our Director, Human Resources by email [privacycanada@yum.com](mailto:privacycanada@yum.com) or by mail as follows:

> **Director, Human Resources**  
>  **Yum Restaurants International (Canada) Company**  
>  101 Exchange Avenue  
>  Vaughan, Ontario  
>  L4K 5R6

### Our Affiliates Subject to this Privacy Policy

The following Yum! Restaurants International (Canada) Company affiliates have adopted and abide by this privacy policy:

  * Yum! Brands Canada Management LP;
  * Yum! Brands Canada Management Holding Company; and
  * Yum! Brands, Inc.

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

This privacy policy is effective as of February 1, 2012. It may be amended from time to time in which event, we will post the revised version here.
